pldt.com.ph 2018-06-13

# Privacy Policy | Official PLDT Website

## 

**

## Our Privacy Commitment 

**The PLDT Group of Companies respects our customers’ fundamental right to privacy, and we commit to take great care in safeguarding your personal data. The PLDT Group has developed a Privacy Policy that aims to ensure that all PLDT Group Companies and Subsidiaries adopt and observe appropriate standards for personal data protection in compliance with Republic Act No. 10173 or the Data Privacy Act of 2012 and its implementing rules and regulations.  While the PLDT Group Privacy Policy sets out the general principles that govern the collection, use, and disclosure of our customers’ personal information, we have also developed this Privacy Commitment to inform you more specifically about our privacy practices. ****

## **Why we collect your personal information  **

If you are a customer of a PLDT Group Company or Subsidiary, we collect and maintain some basic information about you. We do so only for the following purposes:

  * To create and nurture a relationship with you, so that we can continuously provide you with our services. For example, when you apply for any of our services, we collect personal information about you that will allow us to validate your identity and credit history for purposes of billing and collection of fees for the products and services that you avail from us. 
  * To improve our products and services. We collect, use, process, and analyze how you use our products and services so that we can understand how to improve them for your benefit.
  * To understand your needs and preferences so that we can serve you better. Maintaining a record of the products and services that you avail from us allows us to gain a better insight of the kinds of offers that would be relevant to your preferences. From time to time, we may send you product recommendations and special offers that we think will interest you.
  * To continuously improve our business and operations. For example, we analyze customer usage of our network and facilities to help us manage your account, provide customer care activities, monitor the quality and security of the network, train our staff, and plan for future growth.
  * To assist the Government. We generate statistical insights based on your usage of our network and facilities to assist the Government in planning for healthcare, disaster management, and other similar initiatives.  When we can, we aggregate and anonymize this information such that you are never identified as an individual. [Aggregating simply means presenting information in segments or categories like age groups; anonymizing means removing personally identifiable information from the data].
  * To comply with the Credit Information System Act. We run credit scoring programs and initiatives, including but not limited to, providing information to the Credit Information Corporation in accordance to Republic Act No. 9501.
  * To meet legal and regulatory requirements. We perform such other processing or disclosure that may be required under pertinent laws, rules, or regulations.

## **Where we get these information**

**** There are several ways we collect information. 

  **Information that you personally give us.     
**  
Most of the personal information we have are those that you have given us yourself. You provide us personal information when you: 

  * Apply for our services by filling out Application Forms, Subscription Agreements, and other similar or related documents through any of our available channels (online, in our stores, or through our Sales representatives);
  * Get in touch with us to ask about something, file a complaint or request for service;
  * Take part in our research and surveys; 
  * Become our Partner, Vendor, Contractor or Supplier; and/or
  * When you apply for job with us. 

**Information we collect during our relationship with you    
**  
Use our network, facilities and services - whether it is Mobile, Fixed, Home, Enterprise, or any of our other products, services, and channels;

  * Use our network, facilities and services - whether it is Mobile, Fixed, Home, Enterprise, or any of our other products, services, and channels;
  * Pay your bills or purchase add-on products and services;
  * Use our apps, websites, and self-service channels and portals;
  * Join our promos, prize raffles, or rewards & loyalty programs.

**Information we collect from other sources    
**  
We also collect information from commercially or publicly available sources like published directories and public documents. We may also obtain your personal information from third parties and from other sources which you have given separate consent for the disclosure of such information relating to you and where otherwise lawfully permitted.  
****

## **When we disclose personal information**

**** There are a variety of circumstances where we may need to disclose or share some of the information that you have provided to us. In these cases, we ensure that your personal information  is disclosed on a confidential basis, and always subject to the applicable rules and regulations of the Data Privacy Act.

We will never share, rent or sell your personal information to third parties outside of the PLDT Group of Companies except in special circumstances where you may have given your specific consent for, and as noted in this policy.

In some instances, we may be required to disclose your personal information to our agents, subsidiaries, affiliates, partners and other third party agencies as part of our regular business operations and for the provision of our products and services.  This means we might share your information with:  

  * Our partner companies, organizations, or agencies including their sub-contractors or prospective business partners that act as our service providers, contractors, professional advisers who help us provide our products and services.  For example:  our couriers for bill delivery and our customer contact centers for our pre- and post-sales hotline operations;
  * PLDT Group Companies, Subsidiaries, and Affiliates;
  * Subject to applicable laws and regulations, law enforcement and government agencies; and 
  * Other companies whom you have also given consent to share your information.

## How we protect your personal information

The integrity, confidentiality and security of your information are important to us. That’s why we strictly enforce our Privacy Policy within the PLDT Group and have implemented technical, organizational and physical security measures that are designed to protect your information from destruction, unauthorized access, alteration, disclosure, fraudulent misuse and/or any other unlawful processing, as well as other natural and human dangers.

We also put in effect safeguards such as:

  * We keep and protect your information using a secured server behind a firewall, encryption and security controls;
  * We keep your information only for as long as necessary for the fulfillment of the purposes for which the information was obtained or for the establishment, exercise or defense of legal claims, or for legitimate business purposes, or as provided by law;
  * We restrict access to your information only to qualified and authorized personnel who handle your information with strict confidentiality.
  * We undergo regular audit and rigorous testing of our infrastructure’s security protocols to ensure your data is always protected;
  * We promptly notify you and the National Privacy Commission, when sensitive personal information that may, under the circumstances, be used to enable identity fraud are reasonably believed to have been acquired by an unauthorized person;
  * We let you update your information securely to keep our records accurate.

The PLDT Group of Companies will not collect, use, or disclose your personal information for any purpose other than those identified in this Commitment, your Service Agreement or our Terms of Service, and any other purpose that you may have given your consent for.

For greater clarity, unless you provide specific consent, we will not:

  * Share your personal information with or sell it to our business partners and third-party service providers; or
  * Use your personal information to enable third-party targeted advertisements.

## What your choices are

You are afforded certain rights in relation to your personal data under the Data Privacy Act. We would like to ensure that we have your consent to continue to collect, use, and disclose your personal information for the purposes that we have identified. At the same time, we want you to know that you do have choices and can object or withdraw your consent and/or edit your consent preferences at any time:

If you wish to have access to your personal information in our records; or you think that such personal information we have of you is incomplete, not up-to-date, or otherwise inaccurate, you may get in touch with the PLDT Group Data Privacy Officer through the contact details provided below.  In some instances, we may request for supporting documents or proof before we effect any requested changes to your personal information.

  **PLDT Group Data Privacy Office;**  
Address: Ramon Cojuangco Building, Makati Avenue, Makati City 1200 Philippines   
E-mail: dpo@pldt.com.ph

## What happens when there are changes in our Policy

From time to time, we may update our privacy policy and practices to comply with changes in the laws, rules, and regulations, to comply with government and regulatory requirements, to adapt to new technologies and protocols, to align with industry practices, or for other legitimate purposes.

You will always be provided notice if these changes are significant and, if we are required by law, we will ensure to obtain your updated consent.   

_Last updated: June 14, 2017  
_

## Subsidiaries and Affiliates

  * PLDT
  * Smart Communications, Inc.
  * ePLDT
  * Digitel Mobile Philippines, Inc. (Sun Cellular)
  * Voyager Innovations, Inc.
  * Cignal TV
  * FINTQNOLOGIES CORP.
  * PayMaya Philippines, Inc. (formerly Smart eMoney, Inc.)

## Partners

  * 3PL
  * 7 BOX UP
  * 8 Elements Pte. Limited
  * 8Telcom, Inc.
  * ABS-CBN Corporation
  * ACCENT MICRO PRODUCTS INC.
  * Accenture, Inc.
  * Access Mobile Co. Ltd.
  * ACISION UK LTD
  * Activasia
  * ADI ASIANIC DIST. INC.
  * AEROPHONE ENTERPRISES & CO
  * AGSX PH
  * Airtalk Mobile Communications
  * Akromont Marketing Corp.
  * ALCATEL
  * Alliance
  * ALLWORLD CORPORATION
  * Amdocs Phils. Inc.
  * American Express
  * Apple
  * Aptilo
  * Arquillo dela Cruz & Associates Law Offices
  * A-shop
  * Asiadok Inc
  * Asianic
  * AsiaPay Payment Technology Corp.
  * Asiatel
  * Aspire Lifestyle / International SOS
  * Ateneo De Manila University
  * ATLASSIAN SOFTWARE SYSTEMS PTY LTD
  * Auth0, Inc
  * AUTOMATIC APPLIANCE
  * Ayannah InformationSolutions
  * Aztech Solution International Corp.
  * Banana Mobile Group, Inc.
  * BDO
  * Berinne
  * Besdeals, Inc.
  * BESTOPTIONS ASSISTANCE INC.
  * Big Sky Nation, Inc. 
  * Bitmarket.ph Inc.
  * Blackberry
  * Boardwalk
  * Bochitta
  * Boku Network Services Inc.
  * Brandworks
  * Bubble Motion Pte Ltd
  * Bustos Law Office
  * CALL DESIGN
  * CC Mobile Financial Services Philippines Inc.
  * CEBU QINGXIN ENTERPRISE
  * Cebuana Lhuillier
  * Cellcom World Communications
  * CELLEX NETWORKS SYSTEMS (2007) LTD / SMS GLOBAL TECHNOLOGIES LIMITED (SMSHK)/ SMS GLOBAL TECHNOLOGIES INC.
  * Cellon Ltd.
  * Centennial
  * Centili Limited
  * CFSI
  * Charle's Cellzone
  * Chikka Philippines, Inc.
  * Chubb
  * CIBI Information, Inc.
  * Cignal TV, Inc.
  * Cinco
  * Citibank
  * Coda Payments
  * Communigate Technologies, Inc.
  * Compex
  * Complink
  * COMPTEL OYJ / COMPTEL CORPORATION
  * Computerbytes
  * Comworks
  * CONSOLIDATED MANAGEMENT RESOURCES INC.
  * Consumer Republiq
  * Cormant
  * Cortel Law Office
  * Cosmic Digital Universe Inc
  * Creative InfoSolutions, Inc.
  * CTI
  * CTV
  * CURO Teknika Inc.
  * Customer Frontline Solutions Inc. (Bayad Center)
  * D5
  * Dakila Cable TV Corp
  * Dell
  * DIARS
  * DIGILIFE
  * Digital Music Creatives, Inc.
  * Digital Turbine Singapore Private Limited
  * Digitel Mobile Philippines, Inc.  (DMPI)
  * Dimension Data
  * Diners
  * DingLi Corp., Ltd.,
  * Directories Phils. Corp. (formerly ANTS)
  * Dlucky
  * DMN Expats
  * DMPI
  * Dragonpay Corporation
  * DTC
  * Dun & Bradstreet Philippines, Inc.
  * Dwinar
  * EasyTrip Services Corporation
  * Ebiz
  * EL GRANDE MESSENGERIAL SERVICES, INC.
  * Elite Global
  * Eltek
  * EMC
  * Emerson Power
  * ePDS, INC.
  * Equitable Card Network
  * ERICSSON AB / ERICSSON TELECOMMUNICATIONS, INC.
  * E-Science
  * Evamp & Saanga Solutions
  * EVOLVING SYSTEMS LIMITED
  * Excite
  * Experian
  * ExpressPay Inc.
  * Facebook, Inc.
  * FASTRAK SERVICES, INC.
  * Firestarters
  * Firewire
  * First Mobile Phils Inc
  * First Telecom
  * FLASH
  * FLASHER NEXT GEN
  * FONERANGE
  * FONESTYLE ACCESSORIES
  * Forest Interactive Development Incorporated
  * Fortumo OU
  * Fox
  * Fritz and Macziol
  * FUJITSU PHILIPPINES, INC.
  * Funguy Studio  Philippines, Inc.
  * G&D (GIESECKE & DEVRIENT)
  * Galileo
  * Gameloft Philippines, Inc.
  * Garena Philippines Inc.
  * Gate Distribution
  * GBPlay, Inc (formerly PlayOn)
  * Geenger
  * GetResponse Sp. z o.o. (electronic direct mail sending)
  * GFG GROUP LIMITED
  * GFK Philippines
  * GIESECKE & DEVRIENT ASIA PTE LTD
  * Global Pinoy Remittance Services
  * Glyphstudios, Inc.
  * GMA New Media, Inc.
  * GOODLINE
  * Google Asia Pacific Pte. Ltd.
  * Google Inc.
  * Got Deals Mobile Inc
  * Gotuaco, Del Rosario Insurance Brokers, Inc.
  * Great Deal Communications
  * Hand Interactive, Inc. (Buqo)
  * HEWLETT-PACKARD PHILIPPINES CORPORATION
  * Hildawa Law Office
  * HUAWEI INTERNATIONAL PTE. LTD / HUAWEI TECHNOLOGIES PHILS., INC.
  * Hyperlync Technologies Inc.
  * IBM PHILIPPINES, INC.
  * I-Contacts Corp
  * iFlix Sdn Bhd
  * I-Gateway Mobile Philippines, Inc.
  * IMFREE, INC.
  * Indra Philippines, Inc.
  * INDUS SOFTWARE TECHNOLOGIES PRIVATE LIMITED
  * Indus Software Technologies Pvt. Ltd.
  * INFINITE MOBILE SOLUTIONS
  * Info Professionals, Inc.
  * INFOCOM TECHNOLOGIES, INC.
  * INFOMAX SYSTEMS SOLUTIONS & SERVICES INC.
  * INFORMATION EXPRESS SERVICE, INC. (INFORMEX)
  * INFORMATION PROFESSIONALS, INC.
  * Infospring Research
  * INTEC BILLING, INC.
  * Intertraffic Transport Corporation (ITC)
  * INTOGADGETS
  * Ion Management Solution
  * IPay88 Philippines Inc.
  * IPC (IP Converge)
  * IPLUS INTELLIGENT NETWORK, INC.
  * ISPI Global
  * IT Corea
  * IT Managers
  * Ivory Music and Video, Inc. (Sony Ivory)
  * iWant TV
  * JunoTele Pte. Ltd.
  * Kantar Added Value (Saffron)
  * KIMSTORE
  * Kreatif Bersama (Philippines), Inc.
  * Lantro Phils., Inc.
  * Lazada
  * LBC (sub KA: Novellis)
  * Lead Hope Digital Inc.
  * LENOVO / MOTOROLA
  * Lighthouse
  * Linode, LLC
  * LPT Ultramega
  * LRT
  * Mactel
  * Mactelecom Corp.
  * MAIL EXPERT MESSENGERIAL & GEN SERVICES INC.
  * Manila Express Payment
  * MATRIXX SOFTWARE, INC.
  * MCA Music, Inc.
  * Mega Cellular Network, Inc.
  * Megamobile Inc.
  * MEJABS SERVICES. INC.
  * MEMO EXPRESS
  * Meralco
  * MESSAGING SOLUTIONS PROVIDER, INC.
  * Metrobank
  * MICROSOFT PHILIPPINES, INC.
  * Mile10
  * MILES CELLPHONE AND ACCESSORIES
  * Millward Brown Philippines (MB)
  * Mindmap
  * Mineski
  * Mirof
  * Mlhuillier
  * Mobiadvanced Interactive Limited
  * Mobiamo Limited (formerly Paymentwall)
  * Mobile Tech Services (Singapore) Pte. Limited
  * Mobistyle
  * Mobitrans FZ-LLC
  * Monde Nissin
  * Moose Media, Inc.
  * Mountain Dew
  * MTech
  * MUENCHEN CORP
  * MyPhone
  * com Inc.
  * National Bookstore
  * Nazara Technologies
  * NEC PHILIPPINES, INC.
  * Nestle Phils
  * net mobile AG
  * NET1 APPLIED TECHNOLOGIES SOUTH AFRICA (PTY) LTD. 
  * Netwire Solutions Specialist, Inc.
  * NEWNET COMMUNICATION TECHNOLOGIES B.V.
  * Newport Prepaid Solutions
  * Nielsen Philippines
  * NOKIA SOLUTIONS AND NETWORKS OY / NOKIA SOLUTIONS AND NETWORKS PHILIPPINES, INC.
  * Novare
  * Novelis
  * O+ USA
  * Octomind Mobile Content Services
  * OksPinoy Inc.
  * Omni Digital Media Ventures, Inc. (aka Blink)
  * One Asia Touchpoint
  * One Horizon Group, Inc
  * One World Distribution Enterprise
  * Ookbee
  * OPENCODE SYSTEMS LTD
  * Opera Software AS
  * OPPO
  * OPTIMA DIGITAL, INC.
  * ORACLE (PHILIPPINES) CORPORATION
  * Orange & Bronze
  * ORANGE FIX
  * Oxford
  * Pahrsek
  * PAL (Mabuhay Miles)
  * Palawan Pawnshop
  * PBA Properties, Inc.
  * PCN
  * Perez De Tagle, Fabie & Jentes
  * Philippine Survey and Research Center (PSRC)
  * Pitney Bowes
  * Playpark Inc.
  * PLDT GLOBAL
  * POINTMAN PLACEMENT SPECIALIST, INC.
  * Polyeast Records Inc.
  * Power Mac
  * Powerhouse
  * Powerhouse Distributor, Inc.
  * Praise Incorporated
  * Private Communication
  * PROMARK CORPORATION
  * PXI
  * Quicktrax Marketing Corp.
  * RAMLAY PRIME HOLDINGS, INC.
  * RC GOLDLINE
  * RC Goldline
  * Red Dot
  * Red Hat
  * REDKNEE SOLUTIONS (UK) LIMITED / REDKNEE SOLUTIONS INC.
  * Remitbox
  * RGMA Marketing & Productions Inc.
  * Rising Tide Mobile Entertainment, Inc.
  * Robinsons Convenience Store
  * Robinsons Inc
  * Robinsons Ventures
  * RS Santos Law Firm
  * RSC
  * RULLS CELLPHONE AND ACCESSORIES
  * SAFEFREIGHT SERVICES INC.
  * Samsung
  * San Roque Supermarket
  * Sandz Phils
  * SAP PHILIPPINES, INC.
  * SAS Institute (Philippines) Inc.
  * SAVE N EARN
  * Schneider Electric
  * SEARCHERS & STAFFERS CORP.
  * Selecta
  * Sept3 Technology Sdn. Bhd
  * Servflex Inc.
  * Shop4Fun, Inc. (formerly All Serve/Cherry Credits)
  * Siena Mobile
  * SIENNA
  * SILICON VALLEY
  * Sitetel
  * SKK MOBILE
  * Sky Roam
  * SLI
  * SM Mart
  * SM Savings and Loan Association
  * Smart e-Money Inc.
  * Smarty Marketing
  * SMI
  * SMS Global Tech Inc.
  * Sobredilla Law Office
  * Software Lab Inc.
  * SOLVENTO PHILIPPINES, INC.
  * Soprano
  * Speedex
  * SPEEDEX COURIER & FORWARDER, INC.
  * SPI CRM INC.
  * SPI Global
  * CLAIRE (SECURITY)
  * Star Appliance
  * Starmobile
  * STERLING GLOBAL CALL CENTER
  * SUBEX LIMITED
  * Summit Collection and Allied Services
  * Sumo Group Inc.
  * Super 8
  * Supplies Station Inc
  * SurveyMonkey, Inc.
  * SY and JAE Corporation
  * Symantec
  * SYNCHRONOSS SOFTWARE IRELAND LIMITED / SYNCHRONOSS TECHNOLOGIES PHILIPPINES
  * Sysmobile Philippines, Inc. (Binbit)
  * Tangent
  * Tango
  * Taylor Nelson Sofres (TNS)
  * TBWA\Santiago Mangada Puno Advertising, Inc.
  * TECHBOX
  * TERADATA PHILIPPINES,  LLC
  * THE BILL SENDER CORPORATION (TRADE NAME: THE BILL SENDER CORP)
  * The Law Firm of Lauron delos Reyes & Partners
  * The Walt Disney Company (Southeast Asia) Pte. Limited
  * Themeworks
  * Tiaxa
  * Timwe Asia Pacific Sdn. Bhd.
  * Topserve Service Solutions, Inc.
  * Tose Co., Ltd.
  * Trackstar
  * Transmolitor  
  * TransUnion Information Solutions, Inc.
  * Trends and Technologies, Inc.
  * TUDLO INNOVATIONS / OCD
  * Tutuka Software (Pty) Ltd.
  * TV 5
  * Typeform, S.L. (Cloud-based customer surveys)
  * UBER
  * Ultramega
  * Unilever
  * UNIVERSAL RECORD
  * Universal Records
  * Uniwiz Trade Sales, Inc
  * Upstream Marketing Program Limited
  * Usabilla b.V.
  * USSC (CTI local)
  * Vectras
  * Ventaja
  * Venture Lead Data
  * Versatech
  * VILLMAN
  * Vision Critical
  * VIVA Records Corporation
  * Vmobile
  * Vodafone
  * Warner Music Philippines, Inc.
  * Wide Wide World Express Corporation
  * WIDGET CITY
  * Winnable Marketing Corp.
  * WirelessHQ Corp.
  * With Him Trading
  * Xaimecs
  * Xurpas, Inc.
  * Xytrix
  * Yondu Inc.
  * Youphoric Labs (Formerly Striker)
  * YouTube
  * Zed Philippines, Inc.
  * Zendesk Inc.
  * Zingmobile Pte Ltd
  * ZIP BUSINESS SERVICES, INC. 
  * Zong
  * Zuffa International, LLC
